Guide to the Liberia Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Liberia collection
1848-2013
MS 1525
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.27
(8 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to the history of Liberia and current political and social conditions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to the history of Liberia and current political and social conditions.
Women -- Liberia; Liberia -- Armed Forces; Liberia -- Description and travel; Liberia -- Foreign relations; Liberia -- History; Liberia -- Politics and government; Photographs -- Liberia; National Democratic Party of Liberia
- Inventory
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters; magazines, 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Journals: literary and academic, 1974-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Political organizations: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers: general, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Human rights and foreign aid to Liberia: bulletins; journals; pamphlets printed internationally, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Armed Forces of Liberia (AFL): "Program Commemorating the 29th Anniversary of Armed Forces Day", 1986 February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Women's movement/organizations: journals; newsletters; printed materials, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Liberian Mission: volumes I and II of photograph albums by E. Gladden, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Liberian Mission: volume III of photograph albums by E. Gladden, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-189
  - Additional printed materials, 1956, 1980-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Photograph album of John E. Smith [sergeant in U.S. Army], 1944 (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-037
  - The Inquirer, vol. 4, no. 154, 1994 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Liberian Inaugural, vol. 13, no. 12, 1978 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Social Security and Welfare Corporation, "Social Security and You, What Employment Injury Insurance Scheme Means", [1975] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Quinn, Bowden, Institute of Current World Affairs, letter on Monrovia, 1980 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Spectator, inaugural special, vol. 1, no. 1, 1988 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - University of Liberia, "Newsletter," vol.3, no. 1, 1983 June-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional material, 1920-2000s; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1920-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Includes trading cards.
  - Posters, Circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 1)